Haylee McLemore

Los Angeles, CA 91601 | Phone: 864-209-9284 | Email: hmmclemore@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/haylee-mclemore-36339b83/

Github: https://github.com/hayleemclemore

Portfolio: https://hayleemclemore.github.io/Portfolio-HM/

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in web design, application design, providing strong problem-solving skills with a keen eye for aesthetics and presentation. An excellent communicator and collaborator who works well in team-based projects and independently with very strong interpersonal skills.

Technical Skills

Node.Js, Express, JavaScript, jQuery, React.js, Vue.js, React, GIT, GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL, Firebase, Handlebars, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Media Queries, APIs, Microsoft Suite, Heroku, Command-Line, Sketch, Figma, Adobe Creative Suite

Projects

Collocation Creation | Link to Github | Link to Deployed Project

Collocation Creation was inspired by the need for more online study resources for English Language learners worldwide. It combines a dictionary, pronunciation app, thesaurus and a much needed resource to show collocations.

Responsible for UI, API research and search results.

Technologies Used: HTML/CSS, JavaScript, REST API, Bootstrap 4, Google Fonts, AJAX, JSON, iQuery

Sweati | Link to Github | Link to Deployed Project

Sweati is a fitness app to track timing of cardio, mindfulness, and strength training.

Responsible for UI and user authentication, time tracking and testing.

Technologies Used: JavaScript, Node.js, HTML/CSS, Handlebars, Body-parser, Express.js, Passport, bcrypt, bcrypt2

Experience

Plankk; Calgary, CA (Remote)

2020

UI/UX Designer & Front-End Developer (Contract)

Visual design support for B2B Marketing and Product teams.

- Fully designed responsive applications with a user-centered, mobile-first approach.
- Implemented and developed new UI features of application based on designs in Figma
- Designing and maintaining client mobile applications as new features are established
- Responsible for wireframing, designing and prototyping apps and landing pages

Ramsey Solutions; Nashville, TN Designer (Contract)

2020

Visual design support for B2B Marketing and Product teams.

- Designed and maintained marketing email creative, including but not limited to: blog and social graphics, paid media campaign design, print materials, digital web design and other graphic design services.
- Face-lifted two B2B paid media campaigns that doubled in performance of prior campaigns within a 48-hr period.

Speak Creative; Nashville, TN Web Designer/Front-End Developer

2019 - 2020

A mix of design and frontend skills to create a visual identity for clients on multiple platforms with a user-experience driven approach.

- Planned site designs, functionality and navigation, built wireframes and prototypes converted into functional and responsive digital products
- Successfully progressed multiple design projects from concept to execution
- Commonly spearheaded 4+ projects at one time
- Crafted angular components and services with an eye for modularity
- Completed first site build after 6 months
- Tools and applications used mostly HTML, CSS, Javascript, Wordpress, Buddy, Liquid Template Markup

cj Advertising; Nashville, TN

2017 - 2019

Web Designer/Front-End Developer

- Created high-fidelity mockups of web pages for all digital platforms, touched-up photography, designed landing pages, emails, and email graphics
- Designed and maintained highly customized websites based on research and best practice
- Expanded skill set of UI/UX design and digital marketing campaign design
- Commonly handled 5+ projects at any given time, worked under quick turn-arounds in an agency setting
- Promoted from Interactive Print Designer to Web Designer after 6 months
- Kick-started development and design of an internal modular library for web clients

Education

Vanderbilt University; Nashville, TN

Full Stack Web Development | Certificate | 2020

A 24-week intensive boot camp program focused on gaining technical programming and market-driven skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Database Theory, MongoDB, MySQL.

Trevecca Nazarene University; Nashville, TN | 2014-2016

Bachelors of Science | Information Technology and Graphic Media

Clemson University, Clemson, SC | 2012-2014 Bachelors of Science | Graphic Communications